economicsonline.co.uk 2019-04-06

# 1

                                                                                                      1
                     Economics Online Data Protection Policy (with effect from May 25th 2018)
ECONOMICS ONLINE – DATA PROTECTION POLICY
1.  Scope of this policy
    Our privacy policy is intended to explain and clarify how we meet our own expectations
    regarding the privacy of visitors to our website, as well as meet the requirements of the
    new General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), which comes into effect in UK and EU law on
    Friday 25 May 2018.
2.  Privacy notice
2.1 Who are we and what do we do?
      i) Economics Online is an information provider aimed at students of economics at Sixth
           Form and High School, undergraduates, and those studying on professional courses,
           including accounting and business courses. We have been doing this since 2008.
      ii) We take data protection very seriously and understand the importance of protecting
           your privacy and personal information. The personal data we might collect from you
           is strictly limited in scope and is only collected if you make a purchase. Simply visiting
           the site does not require you to provide any personal information. Personal
           information is information that identifies you as an individual such as your name,
           date of birth, email address, IP address and telephone number.
      iii) Our website is hosted by Go Daddy in the USA and you can read their privacy policy
           here.
      iv) Unlike some ‘social media’ companies access to the material on Economics Online
           does not require registration, and there is no registration process and hence no
           personal information is obtained from you by us before you use the site, and while
           you use the site. The information is provided freely to you and all you need to do is
           visit the site. We do not collect personal information because we do not use personal
           information other than to honor contracts with you (see below).
      v)   If you go beyond the freely available information and choose to purchase any
           materials from our store, which is operated by our third-party supplier – Shopify –
           then essential data is collected in order to ensure that the purchase is made
           successfully and the contract to supply is honored.
      vi) Shopify (referred to below more generally as ‘store provider’) is based in the USA, and
           you can view their privacy policy here.
      vii) The personal data collected by Shopify is the minimum necessary to ensure that an
           order placed with us can be fulfilled, and this includes your name, email address to
           send a confirming message that your order is successful, your address, if a physical
           shipment is made, and your telephone number if you choose to provide it. This
           information is only used to facilitate a specific single transaction and is not used for
           any marketing purpose nor is it used by us in any other way other than to enable a
           transaction to be fulfilled. Personal data collected is used solely to enable our store
           provider to fulfil an order that you have placed, and hence complete the legal
           contract to supply you with purchased material. Economics Online may use this data
           only for the purpose of supplying material you have ordered. For example, if a
                    For further information contact us at admin@economicsonline.co.uk

                                                                                                      2
                     Economics Online Data Protection Policy (with effect from May 25th 2018)
           transaction is ‘unsuccessful’ due to an input error we may contact you just to remind
           you that you still have an item in your basket. While we are confident that our third-
           party store provider, Shopify, also only collects data to facilitate specific transactions
           our strong advice is to read their privacy policy to clarify for yourself how they might
           use your data. (See iv above).
     viii) There are numerous links on our website to organisations including the Bank of
           England, the ONS, the UK Treasury, the WTO, the OECD and many national and
           international newspapers, to name a few. These organisations will have their own
           privacy policy and, should they request you to register with them, we strongly advise
           you to consult their privacy policy.
     ix) We have a Facebook page and Twitter page and you are advised to check their data
           protection policies if you have any concerns about how your personal data may be
           used. Facebook’s data policy can be viewed here, and Twitter’s data policy can be
           viewed here.
     x) In order to provide our information service free of charge, we accept advertisements
           on our pages and these are supplied by Google. We strictly control the type of
           advertisement we show. If you have concerns regarding how your data might be
           used please consult Google’s Adsense policy notice, which can be viewed here. In
           summary, their policy states that:
               Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's
               previous visits to a website and other websites.
               Google's use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve relevant ads
               to you based on your visit to our site and/or other sites on the Internet.
               You may opt out of personalised advertising by visiting Ads Settings. (Or you can opt
               out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies for personalised advertising by
               visiting www.aboutads.info.)
2.2 Consent
     i) If you order material through our third-party store provider it is necessary for you to
           provide them with information to enable your order to be fulfilled, and this data will
           be held to enable the order to be fulfilled. Even though we do not use data for any
           marketing purpose or supply your data to third parties, as part of the order process
           you will now be informed about this, and given the opportunity to withdraw future
           consent once the order has been fulfilled.
     ii) You may withdraw consent at any time after the end of the retention period (see
           below) by emailing us at admin@economicsonline.co.uk stating that you ‘do not want
           Economics Online to hold my personal data’. Data will be removed within 12 hours of
           this request.
                   For further information contact us at admin@economicsonline.co.uk

                                                                                                  3
                     Economics Online Data Protection Policy (with effect from May 25th 2018)
2.3 Disclosure
    Economics Online gathers no personal data from you directly and hence will not pass on
    your personal data to third parties. The following third party will receive your personal
    data for the purpose of fulfilling an order placed by you as part of their processing
    activities:
    Shopify Store
2.4 Retention period
      i) Economics Online has access to personal data held by our store provider for the
           purpose of fulfilling an order placed through them – while digital downloads are
           stored on their database there are, from time to time, situations when a download
           has not occurred, or where the link to the material has expired, and in this case,
           Economics Online may fulfil this order directly, but the payment process will be
           managed securely by Shopify and we have no access to financial information.
      ii) To enable us to provide back-up or replacement materials we do keep records of the
           initial transaction including the product ordered, the purchaser’s name, postal
           address and email address. In the interests of being able to keep in contact with a
           purchaser we keep this basic data on our database for a twelve-month period unless
           otherwise instructed by the purchaser or a nominated representative, as indicated
           above. We should be instructed through the original email address you initially used
           to make the purchase.
2.5 Your rights as a data subject
    While we do not collect or store personal information when you visit Economics Online nor
    do we use your data other than to fulfil a specific order if you make a purchase of material
    through our third-party store, we are obliged to inform you of your rights as a ‘data
    subject’, which are:
         • Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we
              hold about you.
         • Right of rectification – you have a right to correct data that we hold about you that
              is inaccurate or incomplete.
         • Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold
              about you to be erased from our records.
         • Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply to have a right to
              restrict the processing.
         • Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you
              transferred to another organisation.
         • Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as
              direct marketing.
         • Right to object to automated processing, including profiling – you also have the
              right to be subject to the legal effects of automated processing or profiling.
         •    Right to judicial review: in the event that Economic Online refuses your request
              under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. You have the
              right to complain as outlined in clause 2.6 below.
    All of the above requests will be forwarded on should there be a third party involved (as
    stated in 2.3 above) in the processing of your personal data.
                    For further information contact us at admin@economicsonline.co.uk

                                                                                            4
                  Economics Online Data Protection Policy (with effect from May 25th 2018)
2.6 Complaints
    In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how your personal data is being
    processed by Economics Online (or third parties as described in 2.3 above), or how your
    complaint has been handled, you have the right to lodge a complaint directly with
    Economics Online’s data protection representatives.
    Our data protection representatives can be contacted directly here:
    (richard@economicsonline.co.uk)
                 For further information contact us at admin@economicsonline.co.uk
